<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TrainingPeaks Translator</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- get fancy for combining definitions for IF to suite both pace and power -->

    <!-- get fancy for combining definitions for EF to suite both pace and power -->

    <!-- combine Aerobic Decoupling for both Pace and Power and get fancy with the definition for combining -->

    <string name="title_activity_display_message">Back to terms</string>
    
    <!-- Glossary of Terms AND Definitions -->
    <string name="tp_term_aerobic">Aerobic</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_aerobic">In the presence of oxygen; aerobic metabolism utilizes oxygen. Below the anaerobic-intensity level.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_anaerobic">Anaerobic</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_anaerobic">Literally, "without oxygen." Exercise that demands more oxygen than the heart and lungs can supply. the intesnity of exercise performed above the lactate threshold.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_anaerobic_endurance">Anaerobic-Endurance</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_anaerobic_endurance">The ability resulting from the combination of speed and endurance allowing the athlete to maintain a high speed for an extended period of time while anaerobic.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_aa_strength_phase">AA Strength Phase: Anatomical Adaptation</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_aa_strength_phase">This is the initial phase of strength training that usually occurs in the late fall or early winter during the Preparation period. It\'s purpose is to prepare the muscles and tendons for the greater loads of the maximum strength (MS) phase.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_atp">ATP: Annual Training Plan</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_atp">The purpose of an annual training plan is to develop a useful and dynamic guide for your training which will allow you to reach your fitness goals. The ATP includes: season goals, supporting objectives, annual training hours, races and events prioritized (A, B, C), training periods, weekly hours, weekly abilities to be emphasized.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_base_period">Base Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_base_period">The period during which the basic abilities of endurance, speed and force are emphasized.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_bt">BT: BreakThrough Workout</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_bt">A workout intended to cause a significant, positive, adaptive response. These workouts can take 24+ hours to recover from. Take extra caution with these workouts.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_build_period">Build Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_build_period">The specific preparation mesocycle during which high-intensity training in the form of muscular-endurance, anaerobic-endurance and power are emphasized, force and speed are maintained.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_cadence">Cadence</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_cadence">Revolutions or cycles per minute of the swim stroke, pedal stroke or running stride.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_calendar_companion">Calendar Companion</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_calendar_companion">The Calendar Companion is a tool in your TrainingPeaks 3.0 Account that allows you to customize the view of your calendar, such as by viewing two calendars side by side or viewing the Calendar view simultaneously with the Dashboard view.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_cp">CP: Critical Power</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_cp">The average power a cyclist can maintain for any given duration of time. Critical power can be used as a parameter for training intensity once a rider\'s CP zones are determined by completing CP field tests. CP zones are expressed as CP followed by the time duration in minutes. Typical CP durations are CP.2 (12-seconds), CP1 (one-minute), CP6, CP12, CP30, CP60, CP90, and CP180.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_cross_training">Cross Training</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_cross_training">Training for more than one sport during the same period of time.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_dashboard">Dashboard</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_dashboard">The Dashboard view in your TrainingPeaks 3.0 Account displays summary pods of various metrics associated with your training and nutrition over a given time period.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_ef">EF: Efficiency Factor</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_ef">Efficiency Factor (EF) is a good measure of your aerobic fitness. By comparing the numbers for similar workouts over several weeks you can measure improvements in aerobic efficiency. If you are making good aerobic progress then your EF will rise over the course of a few weeks. For pace sports, like running, EF is the ratio of normalized graded pace to average heart rate. For sports power sports, like cycling, EF is the ratio of normalized power to average heart rate.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_endurance">Endurance</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_endurance">The ability to persist, to resist fatigue.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_force">Force</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_force">The strength evident in a muscle or muscle group while exerting against a resistance.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_form_sprints">Form Sprints</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_form_sprints">Sprints meant for form not for absolute speed. Do these with a tail wind or slight downhill. Each sprint lasts about 15 seconds with five-minute recoveries. heart rate is not an accurate gauge. Stand for 10 seconds smooth on the pedals building leg strength followed by 5 seconds seated maintaining a high cadence.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_frequency">Frequency</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_frequency">The number of times per week that one trains.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_heart_rate_training_zones">Heart Rate Training Zones</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_heart_rate_training_zones">The Heart rate training zones used on TrainingPeaks.com are based on the athlete\'s lactate threshold heart rate (LTHR). Once the LTHR is determined the five zones can be created by using the &quot;HR \&amp; Power Zones&quot; page calculator found under the Home page. Here is a short description of each zone:\n1-Recovery\n2-Extensive endurance\n3-Intensive endurance/muscular endurance\n4-Sub-threshold\n5a-Super-threshold\n5b-Anaerobic endurance\n5c-Power</string>
    <string name="tp_term_hoods">Hoods</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_hoods">On drop handelbars, the covers of the brake handles.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_if">IF: Intensity Factor</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_if">Intensity Factor® (IF) is an indication of how hard or difficult a ride was in relation to your overall fitness. IF® values are calculated by taking your Normalized Power® (NP) and dividing it by your Functional Threshold Power (FTP).</string>
    <string name="tp_term_intensity">Intensity</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_intensity">The qualitative element of training referring to effort, velocity, maximum strength and power.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_interval_training">Interval Training</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_interval_training">A system of high-intensity work marked by short, but regularly repeated periods of hard exercise interspersed with periods of recovery.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_ilt">ILT: Isolated Leg Training</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_ilt">Pedaling with one leg to improve technique.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_lt">LT: Lactate Threshold</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_lt">The point during exercise of increasing intensity at which blood lactate begins to accumulate above resting levels. Also known as anaerobic threshold.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_lactate">Lactate</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_lactate">Formed when lactic acid from the muscles enters the blood stream.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_lactic_acid">Lactic Acid</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_lactic_acid">A by-product of the lactic acid system resulting from the incomplete breakdown of glucose (sugar) in the production of energy.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_macronutrient">Macronutrient</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_macronutrient">The large category of food, which can be broken down into carbohydrates, fat, protein, and fiber.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_mash">Mash</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_mash">To push a big gear.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_ms">MS: Max Strength Phase</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_ms">The purpose of this phase of strength training is to improve force generation and the ability to teach the central nervous system to easily recruit high numbers of muscle fibers.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_mesocycle">Mesocycle</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_mesocycle">A period of training generally two to six weeks long.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_microcycle">Microcycle</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_microcycle">A period of training of approximately one week.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_me">ME: Muscular Endurance</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_me">The ability of a muscle or muscle group to perform repeated contractions for a long period of time while bearing a load.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_np">NP: Normalized Power</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_np">Normalized Power® (NP®) is an estimate of the power that you could have maintained for the same physiological cost if your power had been perfectly constant instead of variable.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_ngp">NGP: Normalized Graded Pace</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_ngp">Normalized Graded Pace (NGP) is your adjusted pace that reflects the changes in grade and intensity that contribute to the physiological cost of running on varied terrain.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_overreaching">Overreaching</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_overreaching">Training above the work load that would produce overtraining if continued long enough.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_overtraining">Overtraining</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_overtraining">Extreme fatigue, both physical and mental, caused by extensively training at a work load higher than that to which the body can readily adapt.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_pahr">Pa:Hr Aerobic Decoupling</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_pahr">Aerobic Decoupling is the comparison of the efficiency factors for the two halves of the selected interval. If your aerobic decoupling is consistently 5% or less for steady-state aerobic intervals then your aerobic fitness is good.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_pwhr">Pw:Hr Aerobic Decoupling</string>
    <string name="tp_definition">Aerobic Decoupling is the comparison of the efficiency factors for the two halves of the selected interval. If your aerobic decoupling is consistently 5% or less for steady-state aerobic intervals then your aerobic fitness is good.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_peak_period">Peak Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_peak_period">The mesocycle during which volume of training is reduced and intensity is proportionally increased allowing the athlete to reach high levels of fitness.</string>
    <string name="tp_terms_periodization">Periodization</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_periodization">The process of structuring training into periods (Preparation, Base, Build, Race and Transition).</string>
    <string name="tp_term_pod">Pod</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_pod">In your TrainingPeaks.com online account, "Pods" are segmented compartments containing information, data, charts, and reports, which are used to organize your Dashboard, Nutrition, and Workout Details views.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_power">Power</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_power">The ability resulting from force and speed.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_pwrbal">Pwr Bal: Power Balance</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_pwrbal">Power Balance Right is the percentage of power contributed by the right leg to the total power output.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_pe">PE: Power Endurance</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_pe">The purpose of this strength phase is to develop the capacity to quickly recruit most of the fibers for a movement, and to sustain their use at a high power output.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_prep">Prep: Preparation Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_prep">The mesocycle during which the athlete begins to train for the oncoming season; usually marked by the use of cross-training and low loads.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_race_period">Race Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_race_period">The mesocycle during which the work load is greatly decreased allowing the athlete to compete in high-priority races.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_rpe">RPE: Rate of Perceived Exertion</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_rpe">A subjective assessment of how hard one is working.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_recovery_interval">Recovery Interval</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_recovery_interval">The relief period between work intervals within an interval workout.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_recovery">Recovery</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_recovery">A period of training when rest is emphasized.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_rm">RM: Repetition Maximum</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_rm">The maximum load that a muscle group can lift in one attempt. Also called "one-repetition maximum" (1RM).</string>
    <string name="tp_term_repetition">Repetition</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_repetition">The number of times a task, such as a work interval or lifting of a weight, is repeated.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_set">Set</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_set">A group of repetitions.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_sm">SM: Strength Maintenance Phase</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_sm">This weight lifting phase maintains the basic strength established in the previous phases of strength training.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_specificity">Specificity: Principle of Specificity</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_specificity">The theory that training must stress the systems critical for optimal performance in order to achieve the desired training adaptations.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_speed">Speed</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_speed">Within the context of this site, the ability to move the body in ways that produce optimum performance. For example, the ability to turn the cranks quickly on the bike.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_strides">Strides</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_strides">Counting your strides to ensure a certain stride count during a speed/skill development workout is quite common to develop better running posture and economy. A workout may say to count your strides (right or left foot) for a count of 20 seconds and have a goal of 30 strides within the 20 seconds.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_swim_pace_zones">Swim Pace Zones</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_swim_pace_zones">Monitoring swim heart rate is not simple since chest straps tend to slip down while swimming. For this reason few swimmers use them. Counting beats at the end of a set is not very helpful either since the heart rate drops so fast in fit swimmers. Studies have also shown this to be a very inaccurate gauge of effort. The best way to gauge effort in swimming is by pace. Record swim pace zones based on a 1000m/y time trial. This is explained and a chart is shown in "The Triathlete's Training Bible" on pages 44-45.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_tapering">Taper</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_tapering">A reduction in training volume prior to a major competition.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_tops">Tops</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_tops">The portion of the handelbar closest to the stem.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_tss">TSS: Training Stress Score</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_tss">Training Stress Score (TSS) is a composite number that takes into account the duration and intensity of a workout to arrive at a single estimate of the overall training load and physiological stress created by that training session.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_training_zone">Training Zone</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_training_zone">A level of intensity based on a percentage of some measure, such as heart rate or power, of the individual\'s capacity for work.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_transition_period">Transition Period</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_transition_period">The mesocycle during which the work load and structure of training are greatly reduced allowing physical and psychological recovery from training and racing.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_vam">VAM</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_vam">VAM is your average rate of elevation gain in meters per hour. VAM is the abbreviation for the Italian term velocità ascensionale media.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_vi">VI: Variability Index</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_vi">Variability Index (VI) is the measure of how smooth or evenly paced your power output was during a workout. VI is the ratio of normalized power to average power.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_vt">VT: Ventilatory Threshold</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_vt">The point during increasing exertion at which breathing first becomes labored. Closely corresponds with lactate threshold.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_vo2max">VO2max</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_v02max">The capacity for oxygen consumption by the body during maximal exertion, also known as aerobic capacity and maximal oxygen consumption. Usually expressed as liters of oxygen consumed per kilogram of body weight per minute (ml/kg/min).</string>
    <string name="tp_term_volume">Volume</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_volume">A quantitative element of training, such as miles or hours of training within a given time. The combination of duration and frequency.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_warm_up">Warm Up</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_warm_up">The period of gradually increasing intensity of exercise at the start of a training session.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_wkg">W/kg: Watts per Kilogram</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_wkg">Watts Per Kilogram (W/kg) is a great indicator of your ability to perform in hilly terrain and long climbs. W/kg is the ratio of average power in watts to body mass in kilograms.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_work">Work</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_work">Work is the energy transferred to the bike in the form of kilojoules. It is generally accepted in cycling that kilojoules and calories conveniently convert in a 1:1 ratio.</string>
    <string name="tp_term_workload">Workload</string>
    <string name="tp_definition_workload">Measured stress applied in training through the combination of frequency, intensity, and duration.</string>
</resources>
